

# **ERWIN IBARRA V.**

APPIAN LEVEL 2 ENGINEER / .NET DEVELOPER / BPM / MBA WWW.ERWINIBARAV.COM

## **ABOUT**

Born & raised in Saltillo, Mexico. Have a Computer Science bachelor's degree by National Technological Institute of Mexico, and a master's in business administration by TecMilenio University.

Along my 5 years of experience in technology I have had the opportunity to work in 3 different countries for some of the biggest consulting firms worldwide, impacting some of the most important companies around the globe on industries such as travel & communications, energy and health & insurance. I have had the opportunity to work face to face with my clients to add them value during the entire software development life cycle. I have had the grace of training and growing teams.

Twice certified as Appian practitioner. Certified in Project Management Methodologies. Focus on the use of effective code standards on all my endeavors. Have experience with Sail, C# and several technologies of Microsoft platform such as VB, VBA, ASP.NET, T-SQL, WCF, WPF & Azure as well as MVC and other distributed architectures for software development. Worked with Agile and Waterfall methodologies.

## **EDUCATION**

### **MASTER'S IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION**

**TEC MILENIO • JAN 2018 - DEC 2019** 

A master's in business administration program with major in quality and productivity and certification in project management methodologies

#### **COMPUTER SYSTEMS ENGINEER**

**TECNM • JAN 2012 - DEC 2016** 

A computer science bachelor's degree with major in software development

### **BASIC INFO**

**Birthday**: 30/06/1993

Birthplace: Saltillo, Mexico

Citizenship: Mexican

Work Authorization: TN Visa Holder

**Current Location:** Washington DC

Preferred Location: US & UK

Current Rate: Please ask by email

Web Site: www.ErwinlbarraV.com

**Email:** <u>lam@ErwinlbarraV.com</u>

**Phone Number:** 571 352 9742

## LANGUAGES

- Spanish (Native)
- English (Proficient)

## **SOFT SKILLS**

- Planning
- Communication
- Teamwork
- Analytical Thinning
- Leadership



## **ERWIN IBARRA V.**

APPIAN LEVEL 2 ENGINEER / .NET DEVELOPER / BPM / MBA WWW.ERWINIBARAV.COM

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

**HEXAWARE • SITA (UK) • JUL 2019 - CURRENT** 

Development of a product for electronic visa for a UK client that includes the automation in Appian of all the business processes required to issue a visa such as immigration, security and document check. The application allows a user to start a visa application from an integrated frontend in Drupal and provide all required evidences based on the requested visa type, later a group of security officers and visa officers continue the process in Appian till the electronic visa is finally issued.

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

HEXAWARE • BPM LAB (INDIA) • JAN 2019 - JUN 2019

Working for Hexaware's BPM Lab designing innovative solutions such as an application for loan origination that includes all the steps from taking a loan application up to approve it and notify both borrowers and lenders through internal feeds. The application allows borrowers to take an application form, and then it is processed, evaluated and pre-approved or denied by the bank based on the inputs from the borrower.

#### APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT ANALYST

ACCENTURE • INTEGRYS (MEXICO) • JAN 2018 - DEC 2018

A billing solution was maintained and enhanced for energy companies. The process is to resolve defects, extend the functionality of the same by adding new business requirements and migrate the whole legacy application from C++ to C#. Work alongside Minneapolis functional team and product owners in close collaboration to ensure the quality of the product.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Appian
- C#
- VB
- VBA
- ASP.NET
- MvSOL
- T-SOL
- Iava
- WPF
- Rest API
- WCF
- Azure
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Windows
- Linux
- Time Management
- Problem Solving
- Strategic Thinking

## **AWARDS**

HEXAWARE'S BEST DEBUTANT 2017

2ND HIGHEST SCORE OF BATCHES



# **ERWIN IBARRA V.**

APPIAN LEVEL 2 ENGINEER / .NET DEVELOPER / BPM / MBA WWW.ERWINIBARAV.COM

## **EXPERIENCE (CONT.)**

#### **APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT ANALYST**

ACCENTURE • WEC (MEXICO) • JUL 2017 - DEC 2017

Extended functionality for an existing application was developed for client business purposes. We created new desktop applications that helped the client to get the most use of an existing application. We worked close to the WEC team to make sure the first step of this system integration could be accomplished possible following the best industry standards

#### **ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

HEXAWARE • AIG (MEXICO) • JAN 2016 - JUL 2017

Worked alongside Houston & Chennai teams for supporting and maintaining the entire set of enterprise solutions for human resources global department of an important health and insurance company. Bug-fixed, hot fixed and supported Appian applications such as employee performance management system, tuition reimbursement system, enterprise bus system as well as many other integrations with other enterprise solutions.

### JUNIOR DEVELOPER

**APTIV • TLL (MEXICO) • JUN 2015 - DEC 2015** 

We worked in the development of a production tracking system for important manufacturing client. We developed desktop and batch applications for tracking the state of single part number along the entire production process to allow the clients to be able to estimate the current state of the production plan.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **SAFE® AGILIST**

**JUN 2020** 

Certified SAFe® Agilist

#### **SFPC**

**JUN 2020** 

Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate

#### **APPIAN LEVEL 2**

JUL 2019

Appian Practitioner Level 2

#### **PROJECT MANAGEMENT**

**APR 2019** 

Project Management Methodologies based in PM Book certification

### **APPIAN ANALYST**

**MAR 2017** 

**Appian Analyst Certified Practitioner** 

## CONTESTS

APPIAN WORLD HACKATHON 2020

APPIAN WORLD HACKATHON 2019

HACKMTY

2015